# **Natalie Lord**

User Experience Professional
Washington, DC
(703) 606-7516
natalieclord@gmail.com
@nattybowtie

I make websites easy to use by closely studying and listening to users. My background in Marketing and UX means I have a keen understanding of the way user experience design and strategic content can influence sales and customer engagement. I stay current with the latest UX trends and processes through coursework, meetups and conferences. I use Lean UX methodologies and practices that aim to optimize final products so that they better serve their users.

## Education

**General Assembly Front End Web Development Course** 

November 2014-February 2015

Built a responsive website by organically writing HTML, CSS and JavaScript

**General Assembly User Experience Design Course** 

January 2014-April 2014

Built a mobile app by creating user flows, personas, wireframes and a clickable prototype

University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia

May 2012

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature and Language

Semester at Sea

**Spring Voyage 2011** 

Circumnavigated the globe visiting 13 different countries

## **Work Experience**

Associate Information Architect, NavigationArts, McLean, VA

June 2014-Present

Provided exemplar UX consulting services in user research, information architecture, content strategy and usability while working with clients in industries such as e-commerce, communications, energy and technology. I challenged older methods of thought in a legacy digital agency when creating:

- Competitive Assessments
- Content Strategies
- User Interviews and Research
- Usability Testing

### Marketing Assistant, NavigationArts, McLean, VA

March 2013-July 2014

- Optimized social media presence on Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and Pinterest
- Organized marketing campaigns using SEO best practices and Google Analytics
- Wrote thorough case studies and press releases using client research and documentation
- Supported sales team by nurturing leads through Marketo and Microsoft Dynamics CRM
- Maintained and wrote content for the website using Sitecore CMS
- Curated and edited content for the corporate blog published twice a week

# Marketing Assistant, ESL Records, Washington, DC

September 2012-February 2013

- Identified branding and marketing strategies for individual artists
- Managed international online store using Shopify
- Managed social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, MTV.com, Rdio, and Spotify for bands such as Thievery Corporation with over 350,000 fans on Facebook
- Wrote and executed monthly newsletter sent to 14,000 fans using Mail Chimp
- Kept and prepared accurate metadata reports for running royalties for all artists on the label
- Updated the ESL Music Wordpress website daily with news, tour dates, and video content

#### **Specialties**

UX Strategy, Brand Architectures, Brand Strategy, User Research,, Wireframes, Usability Testing, Competitive Assessments, Heuristic Evaluations, Content Auditing, Content Mapping

#### Skills

Proficient in Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Axure, Omnigraffle, Visio, HTML and CSS.